# WILMER RIVERA

Rome, GA

Phone: 706-331-4752 | Email: coding706@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/wilmer88 | Portfolio: https://wilmer88.github.io/blast-porfolio/ |

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/wilmer-rivera-0536291b3

## **S**UMMARY

10 years of professional experience. Two plus years as Full-Stack Web Developer working on and creating databases and connecting them to the front & back-end; using Linux/ Ubuntu, Windows and MACos. Can set up different IDEs with various code editors like IntelliJ, Visual Studio and VS Code. Actively learning new skills on OO design patterns, best practices and building reliable maintainable code using any framework. Successfully refactor projects to a newer version release. Led all the trouble shooting, the designing and launching of all Coat & Code web applications.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Softwares/Platforms: Django, Laravel, React, NoSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS, Oracle, Git,

JQuery, Node, handlebars.

Software Languages: ES6, JavaScript, Python, Java, PHP, C#, HTML5, CSS, C++

#### **PROJECTS**

## taco-stand | github.com/wilmer88/taco-stand | https://taco-stand.herokuapp.com

- Gives business a template to sell their products, where foodies can pre order and make
  online payments, eliminating having to wait in line and the inevitable prepping wait time
  that comes after placing an order; helps to eliminate the need to use man/ woman power
  to take orders and receive payments; vanishes all check delivery times, since paid orders
  are instantly available to kitchen staff.
- Solely responsible for the application idea, the building of all features; in charge of creating, designing and finding solutions, also for writing all of the backend and frontend source code and launching the application.
- Technologies: React/JSX, React Router, Express, Node, MongoDB, Bulma, ES6, Bcrypt, JWT, Mongoose, Axios, Stripe Checkout, JSON Web Token and more, please see dependencies.

## Web-Inventory | github.com/wilmer88/tool-inventory | https://tool-inventory.herokuapp.com

- App enables employees' mobile devices to document items, their location, count, specifications, and the name of the employee that was assigned to count those items, filtering items by department, facilitating a speedy and accurate inventory count.
- Singly responsible for inception of application by writing all the source code, creating the front end design, doing all testing, building all the features and finally launching the app.
- Built with Foundation css framework, Handlebars, HTML, JawsDB MySQL and Sequelize.

## ga\_dev | github.com/wilmer88/err-help | https://ga-devs1.herokuapp.com

- Full CRUD application where jr developers can post their computer errors and solutions.
   Created for developers to save their solutions, their knowledge and ask "dumb questions" all connected to a live database. Works well on desktop, with mobile responsiveness.
   Future development is pending until further notice.
- Lone creator of all backend and frontend code, the view all tab functionality, both edit and delete page functionalities are done. Please see my portfolio for my other projects.
- Project uses: Bootstrap, Django/MVC/ORM, SQLite3, pgAdmin, AWS, and Heroku.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Owner

2020 - Present

#### Coat & Code LLC

Rome, Woodbine Ave

In charge of giving a price for job bids, budgeting and negotiating counter offers, analyzing and comparing offers to other alike jobs for price matching and ensuring fair market price for both client and Coat & Code LLC. In charge of keeping communication with all clients to better understand clients needs and expectations. Responsible for all quality and scheduling before after job completion.

#### Generalist

2013 - 2020

#### MCC LLC

Rome, GA

If needed, responsible for communicating with the leads and managers about the crew's transportation, issues and the tasks that were expected to perform; relay the needs of project materials, tools, and equipment. Using a company Credit Card, going out and purchasing them. One of the trustees to fill out physical paperwork on equipment rentals and purchases. Responsible for driving different company vehicles. Having an excellent work ethic had company clients go out of their way and hand write letters to the project manager on how happy and impressed they were with our work, and how we went above and beyond all expectations.

### **EDUCATION**

## Georgia Institute of Technology: Atlanta, GA

2020 - 2020

An intensive Full Stack Flex Web Development program focused on gaining skills in frontend and backend web development, industry best practices. The creating, connecting to, and working with databases; maintaining legacy code, computer science fundamentals, API architecture, PWA for increased application performance, testing code using test driven development and much more.